Guide to the Isidore Sydney Falk Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Activities, 1919-1979; Series II; 44 linear feet (107 boxes)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund
    - Studies and Reports
      - Study re: relief
        - "Monthly Bulletin on Social Statistics", 1933-1934 (Box 40, Folder 167)
        - Monthly changes in relief statistics, 1934-1935 (Box 40, Folder 168)
        - Miscellaneous publications re: relief, 1932-1933 (Box 40, Folder 169)
        - Working papers, undated (Box 40, Folder 170)
    - Articles
      - "Adequate Health Service for All the People" (J.A. Kingsbury): draft fragment, Circa 1934 April (Box 40, Folder 171)
      - "Adequate Health Service for All the People" (J.A. Kingsbury): final draft, 1934 May (Box 40, Folder 172)
      - "Considerations of the Medical Care of Large Communities" (J.A. Kingsbury, A. Newsholme): correspondence, draft, 1934 (Box 41, Folder 173)
      - "Cooperation in Public Health Work" (J.A. Kingsbury): reprint, Circa 1928 (Box 41, Folder 174)
      - "A Program for National Health Insurance" (I.S.F.): fragment, 1933 November (Box 41, Folder 175)
    - Miscellany
      - Survey forms, 1935-1936 (Box 41, Folder 176)
      - Articles re: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1935 (Box 41, Folder 177)
      - Memoranda re: medical care and M.M.F. programs, 1933-1936 (Box 41, Folder 178)
      - Clippings, 1933, 1935-1936 (Box 41, Folder 179)
      - Miscellaneous materials re: California, Circa 1934 (Box 41, Folder 180)
  - Committee on Economic Security
    - Correspondence
      - A (Box 41, Folder 181)
      - Altmeyer, Arthur J., 1935 March-1936 January (Box 41, Folder 182)
      - Benjamin, Paul L., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 183)
      - Bierring, Walter L., 1935 (Box 41, Folder 184)
      - Brown, Philip King, 1934 (Box 41, Folder 185)
      - Brundage, Dean K., 1934 November-1935 April (Box 41, Folder 186)
      - C (Box 41, Folder 187)
      - Collins, Selwyn D., 1935 (Box 41, Folder 188)
      - D (Box 41, Folder 189)
      - Davis, Michael M., 1934, 1935 January-May, 1935 April-1936, undated (Box 41, Folder 190-193)
      - Eliot, Martha M., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 194)
      - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, 1934 (Box 41, Folder 195)
      - Fischelis, Robert P., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 196)
      - Gourley, Lawrence L., 1935 (Box 41, Folder 197)
      - H (Box 41, Folder 198)
      - Halsey, Olga S., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 199)
      - Harris, Joseph P., 1935 (Box 41, Folder 200)
      - Hincks, Clarence M., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 201)
      - Hopkins, Harry L., 1934 April-1935 January (Box 41, Folder 202)
      - J (Box 41, Folder 203)
      - K (Box 41, Folder 204)
      - Kellogg, Paul, 1935 (Box 41, Folder 205)
      - L (Box 41, Folder 206)
      - Leland, R.G., 1934 November-1935 Jan, undated (Box 41, Folder 207)
      - Leven, Maurice, 1934 December-1935 March (Box 41, Folder 208)
      - Martin, Franklin H., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 209)
      - Narat, Joseph K., 1934 (Box 41, Folder 210)
      - Nordholm, Alex G., 1934 October-1935 May (Box 41, Folder 211)
      - 0-P (Box 41, Folder 212)
      - Perkins, Frances, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 213)
      - Perrott, George St. J., 1935 (Box 42, Folder 214)
      - R (Box 42, Folder 215)
      - Roche, Josephine, 1935 January-1936 January, undated (Box 42, Folder 216)
      - S (Box 42, Folder 217)
      - Schapper, M.B., 1934 (Box 42, Folder 218)
      - Sinai, Nathan, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 219)
      - Sydenstricker, Edgar, 1934 September-1935 August (Box 42, Folder 220)
      - Thompson, Lewis R., 1934 December-1935 May (Box 42, Folder 221)
      - Tucker, Katherine, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 222)
      - Underwood, Felix, 1934 December-1935 January (Box 42, Folder 223)
      - United Medical Service, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 224)
      - Walker, W. Frank, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 225)
      - Waller, Clifford E., 1935 (Box 42, Folder 226)
      - Ward and Paul, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 227)
      - West, Olin, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 228)
      - Williams, Aubrey, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 229)
      - Wilson, Lilith M., 1935 (Box 42, Folder 230)
      - Witte, Edwin E., 1934 August-1935 Jun, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 231)
    - Advisory Committees
      - Dental Advisory Committee: correspondence and membership lists, 1934-1935, 1937, undated (Box 42, Folder 232)
      - Hospital Advisory Board: correspondence, draft report, 1934-1935, 1937, undated (Box 42, Folder 233)
      - Medical Advisory Board: correspondence, 1934-1935, undated (Box 42, Folder 234)
      - Medical Advisory Board: lists with recommendations re: prospective members, Circa 1934-1935 (Box 42, Folder 235)
      - Medical Advisory Board: proceedings of meeting, 1935 January 29-30 (Box 42, Folder 236)
      - Nursing Advisory Committee: membership lists, 1935, 1937, undated (Box 42, Folder 237)
      - Public Health Advisory Committee: membership lists, 1937, undated (Box 42, Folder 238)
      - Advisory Council: materials presented during introductory meeting, 1934 November 15 (Box 42, Folder 239)
    - Reports
      - Schedules for studies, Circa 1934-1935 (Box 42, Folder 240)
      - "Social Security and Public Welfare in the United States"(I.S.F.), drafts, 1934 June (Box 42, Folder 241)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," outline, 1934 November 12 (Box 43, Folder 242)
      - "Abstract of a Program for More Adequate Public Health Services" (preliminary draft of chap. III of final report, ca. 1935 .Jul), mimeograph, 1934 November 15 (Box 43, Folder 243)
      - "Abstract of a Program for Public Medical Services" (preliminary draft of chap. IV of final report, ca. 1935 Jul), mimeograph, 1934 November 15 (Box 43, Folder 244)
      - "Abstract of a Program of Social Insurance Against Illness" (preliminary draft of chap. VI of final report, ca. 1935 Jul), mimeograph, 1934 November 15 (Box 43, Folder 245)
      - Working papers (Myers and Nordholm tables), 1934 November (Box 43, Folder 246)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," draft, 1934 December 4, 1934 December 15 (Box 43, Folder 247-248)
      - Report to the President of the Committee on Economic Security and Supplement to the Report …, 1935 January 15 (Box 43, Folder 249)
      - "Interim Report", 1935 January 21 (Box 43, Folder 250)
      - "Old Age Security Staff Report", Circa 1935 January (Box 43, Folder 251)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," draft (E. Sydenstricker, I.S.F.), 1935 February 14 (Box 43, Folder 252)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," minutes re: February draft, 1935 March 4-5 (Box 43, Folder 253)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," draft (E. Sydenstricker, I.S.F.), 1935 March 19-20 (Box 43, Folder 254)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," correspondence re: March draft, 1935 March-April (Box 43, Folder 255)
      - "Report of the Committee on Economic Security to the President / Final Report on Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Illness," drafts, 1935 March (Box 43, Folder 256)
      - "Report of the Committee on Economic Security to the President / Final Report on Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Illness," final mimeograph, Circa 1935 March-April (Box 43, Folder 257)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health," draft (E. Sydenstricker, I.S.F.), 1935 April 10 (Box 43, Folder 258)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising From Ill Health," correspondence re: report, 1935 June (Box 43, Folder 259)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising From Ill Health," final typescript (chap. I-V), Circa 1935 July (Box 43, Folder 260)
      - "Risks to Economic Security Arising From Ill Health," final typescript (chap. VI, appendices), Circa 1935 July (Box 43, Folder 261)
      - "Recommendations Regarding Risks to Economic Security Arising Out of Ill Health" (outline by executive director), draft, undated (Box 44, Folder 262)
      - "Social Security Against the Risks of Illness," outline, undated (Box 44, Folder 263)
    - Legislation
      - Economic security bills, S. 1130 and H.R. 4539, 74th Congress, first session, 1935 January (Box 44, Folder 264)
      - Social Security Act, H. R. 7260, 74th Congress, first session, 1935 April (Box 44, Folder 265)
      - Social Security Act, reports, summaries, etc., Circa 1935 April-May (Box 44, Folder 266)
    - Miscellany
      - Clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 44, Folder 267)
      - Executive orders and addresses, 1934-1935 (Box 44, Folder 268)
      - Minutes, 1934 Sep, 1935 March (Box 44, Folder 269)
      - Miscellaneous data, 1934-1936 (Box 44, Folder 270)
      - Miscellaneous notes, critiques, and documents, 1935, undated (Box 44, Folder 271)
      - Miscellaneous tables, memoranda, and reprints re: disability insurance, Circa 1934-1935 (Box 44, Folder 272)
      - National Conference on Economic Security (1934 Nov 15), announcement, 1934 November 10 (Box 44, Folder 273)
      - Releases, general, 1934-1935 (Box 44, Folder 274)
      - Releases re: specific topics, 1934-1935, undated (Box 44, Folder 275-276)
      - "Standards of Public Health Organizations Recommended by the Conference of State and Local Health Officers with the Public Health Service…", 1935 June 17-19 (Box 44, Folder 277)
      - "Toward Economic Security," radio symposium, 1935 March 16 (Box 44, Folder 278)
      - Washington State Medical Association, Report of the Economics Committee, 1933-1934 (Box 44, Folder 279)
  - Social Security Administration, Bureau of Research and Statistics
    - General Papers
      - Administrative files
        - Memoranda and annual reports of the division for 1940-1941, 1937-1941 (Box 45, Folder 280)
        - Correspondence re: Interdepartmental Committee to Coordinate Health and Welfare Activities, 1938-1939 (Box 45, Folder 281)
        - Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 45, Folder 282)
        - Memoranda, 1942-1944 (Box 45, Folder 283)
        - Correspondence and memoranda re: American Medical Association, 1943-1951 (Box 45, Folder 284)
        - Bills, hearings and reports re: Federal Security Agency appropriation, 1944-1945 (Box 45, Folder 285)
        - Notes and outlines for talks presented at commissioner's and director's conferences (I.S.F.), 1944-1951 (Box 45, Folder 286)
        - Memoranda and draft legislation re: reorganization of Federal Security Agency, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 287)
        - Correspondence and related materials re: National Physicians' Committee for the Extension of Medical Service, 1946-1948 (Box 45, Folder 288)
        - Notes and outlines for talks presented at regional staff meetings (I.S.F.), 1946-1951 (Box 45, Folder 289)
        - Correspondence criticizing Bureau of Research and Statistics, 1946-1953 (Box 45, Folder 290)
        - Memoranda, 1947-1949 (Box 45, Folder 291)
        - Bills and reports re: Federal Security Agency appropriation, 1948 (Box 45, Folder 292)
        - Correspondence, 1948-1953 (Box 45, Folder 293)
        - Bill and hearings, 1949 (Box 45, Folder 294)
        - Correspondence and memoranda re: proposed libel action by I.S.F., 1949-1950 (Box 45, Folder 295)
        - Memoranda, personnel and budget summary for 1936-1953, 1950-1953 (Box 45, Folder 296)
      - Desk calendars and diaries
        - Desk calendar, 1938-[1939?], 1947 (Box 46, Folder 297-299)
        - Desk diary re: United Steelworkers Union pension problems, Mission to Japan (Harness Committee), O. Ewing's health conference, job classification within division, 1947 May 8-1948 April 11 (Box 46, Folder 300)
        - Desk calendar, 1948-1950 (Box 46, Folder 301-303)
        - Desk calendar, 1951 (Box 47, Folder 304)
        - Desk diary re: trip to Denver, San Francisco, Los Angeles and Seattle, 1951 October-November (Box 47, Folder 305)
        - Desk diary re: S. 3001 (O.A.S.I. hospitalization bill), MagnusonCommittee, Dewey Anderson, job termination, Haiti trip (ceremonies and decoration), 1952 April-1953 December (Box 47, Folder 306)
        - Desk calendar, 1952-1953 (Box 47, Folder 307-308)
      - Personnel file, I.S.F.
        - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 48, Folder 309)
        - Correspondence, application forms and academic transcript, 1937 (Box 48, Folder 310)
        - Correspondence and application forms, 1938-1950 (Box 48, Folder 311)
        - Payroll change slips and related forms, 1938-1954 (Box 48, Folder 312)
        - Service rating forms, 1941-1952 (Box 48, Folder 313)
        - Correspondence and notes re: Board of Inquiry on Employee Loyalty, 1950-1954 (Box 48, Folder 314)
        - Correspondence, application forms and certificate, 1951-1955 (Box 48, Folder 315)
        - Newsclippings re: position changes, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 316)
      - Transition to Eisenhower Administration
        - Memoranda and presidential message re: policy changes, 1953 February-August (Box 48, Folder 317)
        - Newsclippings and related material re: A.J. Altmeyer, 1953 April-July (Box 48, Folder 318)
        - Notes, newsclippings and news releases re: appointments and dismissals, 1953 April-December (Box 48, Folder 319)
        - Speech texts (Oveta Culp Hobby), 1953 April 16-September 13, 1953 September 24-1954 April 4 (Box 48, Folder 320-321)
        - Speech texts (Nelson Rockefeller), 1953 September 29-November 12 (Box 48, Folder 322)
        - Speech texts (Charles S. Keefer), 1953 November 3-December 9 (Box 48, Folder 323)
        - Miscellaneous newsclippings and news releases, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 324)
        - Memorandum re: investments and earnings of O.A.S.I. trust fund (I.S.F.), 4 drafts, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 325)
    - Congressional Investigations
      - Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments, Subcommittee on Publicity and Propaganda (Harness Committee)
        - General papers
          - Hearings and related materials, 1947 May 28-June 18 (Box 48, Folder 326)
          - Third intermediate report, 1947 July 2 (Box 48, Folder 327)
          - Correspondence re: third intermediate report, 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 328)
          - Correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 48, Folder 329)
          - Memoranda (I.S.F., M. Klem, I. C. Merriam) re: health workshops, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 330)
          - Reference materials, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 331)
          - Speech texts, 1947 September 29, October 2 (Box 49, Folder 332)
          - Print materials, 1947-1950 (Box 49, Folder 333)
          - Correspondence and memoranda re: F.B.I. investigation of proposed field trips, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 334)
          - Correspondence and memoranda re: F.B.I. investigation of I.S.F., Bureau of Research and Statistics and Jacob Fisher, 1947 February-Dec, 1948-1954 (Box 49, Folder 335)
          - Lists of material given to F.B.I., 1947 (Box 49, Folder 336)
          - Correspondence and notes re: F.B.I. investigation of Jacob Fisher, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 337)
          - Correspondence and memoranda re: Japan Mission, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 338)
          - Notes and summaries re: Japan Mission, 1947-1948 (Box 49, Folder 339)
          - News releases re: Japan Mission, 1947 August-1948 July (Box 49, Folder 340)
          - Reference materials re: Japan Mission, 1947 October-1948 August (Box 49, Folder 341)
          - Final report, 1948 December 31 (Box 49, Folder 342)
        - Background materials
          - Correspondence and memoranda re: Labor Research Group, 1940-1941, 1946-1947, 1943-1946 (Box 49, Folder 343-344)
          - Notes and memoranda given F.B.I. by Falk, 1943-1947 (Box 49, Folder 345)
          - Correspondence given H. Huffman by Falk, 1945-1946 (Box 49, Folder 346)
          - Reports from Statistical Reporter re: Labor Research Group, 1945-1947 (Box 49, Folder 347)
          - Summarized proceedings re: Conference of Labor Research Group, 1946 December 10-11 (Box 49, Folder 348)
          - Travel history, 1946-1947 (Box 49, Folder 349)
      - Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Subcommittee on Health (Taft-Donnell Committee)
        - General papers
          - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 350)
          - Notes re: Falk's participation in bill drafting, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 351)
          - Correspondence and notes re: Falk's participation in bill drafting, 1947-1952 (Box 49, Folder 352)
          - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1948-1952 (Box 49, Folder 353-354)
          - Correspondence re: Maurice Friedman, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 355)
          - Text of statement (Maurice Friedman), 1947 June 25 (Box 49, Folder 356)
          - Notes and analysis of Maurice Friedman's statement, 1947 June 25 (Box 49, Folder 357)
          - Notes and related materials re: International Labor Office, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 358)
          - Correspondence, notes and related print materials re: Medical Economics, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 359)
          - Text of testimony (Marjorie Shearon), 1948 June 30 (Box 50, Folder 360)
          - Transcript, notes and related materials re: Falk testimony, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 361)
          - News clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 362)
          - Print material, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 363)
          - Print material re: Maurice Friedman, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 364)
        - Background material
          - Print material, 1927-1946 (Box 50, Folder 365)
          - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1929, 1933-1944 (Box 50, Folder 366)
          - Correspondence and notes re: Social Security staff, 1936-1948 (Box 50, Folder 367)
          - Memoranda, notes and related materials re: bill drafting, 1943-1946 (Box 50, Folder 368)
          - Correspondence, memoranda and notes, 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 369)
          - News clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 50, Folder 370)
          - Correspondence, notes and article re: Medical Economics, 1946 Jul, 1945-1946 (Box 50, Folder 371)
          - Correspondence and article re: Rocky Mountain Medical Journal 1946 Apr, 1946 April-September (Box 50, Folder 372)
          - Notes (I.S.F.) and article re: Blueprint for the Nationalization of Medicine (M. Shearon) 1947, 1947 January-May (Box 50, Folder 373)
      - Marjorie Shearon papers
        - History of draft amendment to the Social Security Act, 1938 (Box 50, Folder 374)
        - Biographical data, memoranda and notes compiled by Falk, 1945-1953 (Box 50, Folder 375)
        - Writings
          - Blueprint for the Nationalization of Medicine, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 376)
          - Pamphlets, Nos. 1-5, 1947-1948 (Box 51, Folder 377)
          - Texts of testimony, 1949-1950 (Box 51, Folder 378)
          - Old Doc Truman's Pink Pills, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 379)
          - American Medicine and the Political Scene, 1947 January, July-Dec, 1948 January-Dec, 1949 January-Dec, 1950 January-May (Box 51, Folder 380-385)
          - Challenge to Socialism, 1950 June-Dec, 1951, 1952 January-June, 1953 January-March (Box 51, Folder 386-390)
          - Challenge to Socialism, 1953 April-May, 1954 March-Aug, 1955 January-Aug, 1956 June-Jul, 1958 February-June (Box 52, Folder 391-398)
        - History of service rating appeal, 1941-1942 (Box 52, Folder 399)
        - Newsclippings and print material, 1946-1950 (Box 52, Folder 400)
        - News releases, 1946-1950 (Box 52, Folder 401)
    - International Files
      - Canada
        - Memoranda re: proposed health insurance program, 1943-1944, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 402)
        - Correspondence and print material re: Agnew Point System, 1943-1948 (Box 52, Folder 403)
        - Correspondence and reports re: health insurance proposals (I.S.F., M.M. Davis, D. Gerig, M.L. Plumley), 1943-1948, 1952-1953 (Box 52, Folder 404)
      - Great Britain, National Health Service
        - General papers
          - Memorandum to President Roosevelt, "Comparison of the Beveridge Plan with the Present and Proposed Social Security Systems for the United States" (W.J. Cohen), 1942 December 4 (Box 52, Folder 405)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1942-1946 (Box 52, Folder 406-407)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1947-1948 (Box 53, Folder 408)
          - Reports, notes and related material, 1949-1952, undated (Box 53, Folder 409)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1949-1953 (Box 53, Folder 410)
        - Reference file
          - American Medical Association articles, 1934-1950, undated (Box 53, Folder 411)
          - British Information Service newsletters and pamphlets, 1947-1952, undated (Box 53, Folder 412)
          - British Medical Association articles, pamphlets and related materials, 1930, 1943-1944, 1948-1950 (Box 53, Folder 413)
          - Ministry of Health reports and pamphlets, 1944-1953 (Box 53, Folder 414)
          - Ministry of National Insurance leaflets and pamphlets, 1948-1949, 1951 (Box 53, Folder 415)
          - National Health Service notes and leaflets re: programs and services, 1948-1952 (Box 53, Folder 416)
          - Parliamentary reports, proceedings, and bills, 1942, 1944, 1946 (Box 54, Folder 417)
          - Parliamentary acts, 1946, 1948-1950 (Box 54, Folder 418-419)
          - Social Security Administration publications, 1938, 1943-1944 (Box 54, Folder 420)
          - Journal and magazine articles, 1939, 1941-1951 (Box 54, Folder 421-423)
          - News clippings, 1935, 1939, 1942-1951, undated (Box 54, Folder 424-426)
          - Reports and publications, 1936, 1942-1943 (Box 54, Folder 427-428)
          - Reports and publications, 1944, 1947-1952 (Box 55, Folder 429)
      - Haiti study
        - Administrative papers
          - "Assurances sociales et conditions de travail", 1949 October (Box 55, Folder 430)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1950 January-June (Box 55, Folder 431)
          - Project chronology, 1950 February-September (Box 55, Folder 432)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1950 July-December (Box 55, Folder 433)
          - Notebook and diary from Haiti trips (I.S.F.), 1950 Oct, 1951 February-March (Box 55, Folder 434)
          - Haitian social insurance law, draft revision (Francois Latortue?,), Circa 1950 November (Box 55, Folder 435)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1951 January-April (Box 55, Folder 436-437)
          - "Report on the Social Insurance Program in Haiti" (I.S.F.), 1951 April (Box 55, Folder 438)
          - "Report on the Social Insurance Program in Haiti" (I.S.F.), draft appendix materials, Circa 1951 April (Box 55, Folder 439)
          - Haitian social insurance law, draft revision (I.S.F.), 1951 May (Box 55, Folder 440)
          - Decree amending Haitian civil pension law, Circa 1951 May (Box 55, Folder 441)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1951 May-December (Box 55, Folder 442)
          - Haitian social insurance law, draft revision (Francois Latortue?), 1951 June (Box 56, Folder 443)
          - Haitian pension retirement fund bill, 1951 October (Box 56, Folder 444)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1952 January-June (Box 56, Folder 445)
          - Telephone and work notes re: I.D.A.S.H. consultant, 1952 February-July (Box 56, Folder 446)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1952 July-December (Box 56, Folder 447)
          - Point IV assistance program, monthly reports l and 2 (Douglas J. Galbraith), 1952 November-December (Box 56, Folder 448)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1953 January-June (Box 56, Folder 449)
          - Point IV assistance program, monthly reports 3 and 4-(Douglas Ga1braith), 1953 January-May (Box 56, Folder 450)
          - Point IV assistance program, final reports (Douglas J. Galbraith), 1953 June (Box 56, Folder 451)
          - Correspondence and notes, 1953 July-Dec, 1958 January-February (Box 56, Folder 452)
        - Background information
          - "Absenteeism," reprint, 1943 (Box 56, Folder 453)
          - L'Association Medicale Haitienne: miscellaneous bulletins, 1948, 1951 (Box 56, Folder 454)